大家好，我是A. Jesse Jiryu Davis
Hi, I'm A. Jesse Jiryu Davis
我将解释Python协程是如何工作的
and I'm going to tell you how Python coroutines work.
介绍一下我自己
Little about me,
我是MongoDB的一名高级工程师，职责是为MongoDB写Python和C的驱动。
I work for a MongoDB,I'm a staff engineer, there work on the Python and the C drivers for MongoDB.
是的,我们正在招聘。我强烈推荐来MongoDB工作
Yes, we are hiring and I highly recommend working for MongoDB.
访问Mongo-jobs（https://www.mongodb.com/careers）了解所有的工作机会
You can go to Mongo-jobs to see all of the jobs that we've got open.
如果你想了解更多关于这个视频的信息
And if you want more information about this talk,
我在bit.ly/coroutines中新增了一个页面
I've set up a landing pages at bit.ly/coroutines
你可以在链接里找到本视频的代码
You can find links there to the code that I'm going to write right now,
同时，在即将发布的《开源应用程序架构》书中
and also to a chapter in the upcoming architecture of open source applications book
我和Guido(Python创始人)合著了一章，其中深入地阐述了python协程工作的细节
that I co-wrote with Guido Van Rossum that goes into far more depth and is a very detailed exposition of python coroutines work.
这个演示的主题是
So the agenda for this demo is going to be a
基于回调的异步框架
callback-based async framework,
写完之后，我们会看到它非常有效，但也有些混乱
and once we've written that we're going to see that it's very efficient but also kind of a mess,
所以我们最后要把它改写成一个基于协程的框架
and so we're going to adapt that to a coroutine based framework instead.
因此 从一个基于回调的异步框架入手
So to begin with a callback based async framework,
它使用非阻塞套接字
It uses non-blocking sockets.
使用回调函数
uses the callbacks,
当然
of course,
它还使用一个事件循环
and it also uses an event loop.
至于协程
And as for coroutines,
到时候再说吧
well, we'll cross that bridge when we come to it.
编码之前有一些准备工作
So a little bit of setup,
我写了一个简单的web服务器(Github代码中的server.py)
I've written a simple web server and.
它可以响应http请求
It can respond to an HTTP request.
我为本地的python会议"PyGotham"写了这篇文章
I wrote this for a local python conference PyGotham 2015,
所以你可以看到它向所有那些了不起的人们致意
so you can see that it says hello to all of the incredible people there.
这个框架的另一个有趣之处是它有些迟缓
And the other interesting thing about this framework is its kind of slow.
这个web服务器返回非常简单的响应
This web server returns very simple response,
但我增加了一些代码 所以服务器要花差不多一秒钟的时间响应
but I've coded it so that it takes almost a second to reply.
*这非常重要
And so that's going to end up being very important,
因为这是最适合用异步优化的场景：
because that's the sort of thing that async is optimized for.
与速度太慢的服务器或者客户端有效率地通信
Is for talking too slow servers or slow clients efficiently.
让我们看看
So let's see,
我们怎样才能以典型的python方式获取URL
how would we fetch a URL in the kind of typical python way.
所以我们先导入socket
so we would need to import socket right?
然后
And?
绑定到合适的域名和端口
Connected to the proper domain and port.
格式化一个请求
we format a request
把它发送到服务器
then we would send it to the server.
我用的python3环境
And I'm going to do this in Python 3
所以对那些通过网络传输的所有内容进行编码是很重要的
and so it's important to encode everything that we're going to send over the wire.
哦
Oh,
另一个需要记住的重要的事情是
and the other important thing to remember is that.
每个HTTP请求头部以两个回车换行符分隔
Each HTTP requests end in a double carriage return to a new line
所以一旦我们发送了请求就会收到响应 它会以分块的形式返回给我们
so once we've sent the request were going to receive the response and that'll come back to us in chunks.
所以我们要把它们收集到一个列表中
so we're just going to collect those in a list.
收集最多1000个分块(口胡)
Receive them up to a thousand chunks
一次接收1000字节
a thousand bytes at a time,
只要我们接收完一个分块
and as long as we've got a chunk.
就将它加到列表中，如果我们得到一个空的块
will append it to the list and if we get an empty chunk,
我们就知道服务器把我们挂起了
then we know that the server is hung up on us.
所以数据就接收完毕了
so our reception is complete,
所以消息体(body)将会是
and so the body is going to be....
我们将用空字节类型来连接所有的块
We'll use the empty bye to join all the chunks.
然后我们会解码
And then we'll decode that.
默认是utf-8
The utf-8 by default.
然后我们把消息体的第一行打印出来
And then let's just prints the first line of the body.
所以
So,
因为我们在死循环中
and since we're in an infinite loop,
我们需要返回
we need to return,
这就是我们的get函数。如果我们get参数/foo
so that's our get function and if we get that path Foo
运行程序,可以看到响应的第一行是http 200 OK
and if I run this, you'll see that the first line of the response is an http 200 OK.
然后
And?
让我们看看
Let's also see.
整个过程的运行时间
How long that took
这需要大约一秒钟的时间 因为还有Python解释器的一点开销
So it takes about a second because there's a little bit of overhead in the Python interpreter.
这种方法的问题是 如果我们想要访问两个url
the problem with this approach is that if we want to get 2 Urls,
就需要两秒钟 因为我们是串行地获取URL
it's going to take two seconds because we get them serially.
典型方法是在两个线程上启动这两个get操作
And the typical approach to this might be to launch these two operations on two threads,
但如果我们等待数百个缓慢的请求，效率可能会变得非常低
but that might become inefficient if we're waiting for hundreds of slow requests,
因为我们不得不为这些请求创建数百个线程
and we have to spawn hundreds of threads for them.
有很多的开销是不必要的
There's a lot of overhead though it's not necessary,
所以我们将尝试写一个异步的框架来代替它
so we're going to try out making an async framework to do it instead,
这样我们就不需要为了执行数百次缓慢的I/O请求而创建数百个线程了
so that we don't have to spawn hundreds of threads in order to do hundreds of slow i/o operations,
我们想要比这更有效率的办法
we want to be more efficient than that.
所以
So.
异步框架可以使用非阻塞套接字，python中实现非阻塞的基本框架非常简单
A async framework could uses non-blocking sockets and in python making socket non blocking is very simple.
如果我们运行程序，将会发生什么
Now what's going to happen if we run this?
我们会得到一个异常，因为
We're going to get an exception because.
一个非阻塞套接字的意思是任何会阻塞的操作
A non blocking socket what that means is any operation that would block,
就像连接操作，要么立即成功 要么抛出异常
like connecting,either succeeds immediately or raises an exception.
对
Right.
它是不允许阻塞的
It's not allowed to block.
不允许一直等待直到程序成功完成操作
it's not allowed to wait for success.
所以我们需要一些方法来等待它完成
So we need some way to wait for that to complete.
我们用Python来做这个
And the way we do that in Python.
嗯
Well,
首先
first of all,
我们可以先忽略这个错误
we can just ignore that error.
但这不会让我们走得太远因为一旦我们试着发送套接字的东西就会说它还没有连接起来因为当我们调用connect时
But that's not going to get us very far because as soon as we tried to send something of the socket is going to say that it's not connected yet right because when we called connect,
这个旋钮开始了操作
the knob blocking socket began the operation.
但它并没有等待平均完成
But it didn't wait for the average to complete.
所以我们还没有准备好发送它
And so we're not ready to send it yet.
那么我们怎么知道什么时候我们准备好发送一个操作呢
So how do we know when we're ready to send an operation?
嗯
Well,
python3
python three.
有一个叫做选择器的方便模块
There's this handy module called selectors.
然后呢
And?
在每一个操作系统中
In every operating system since time immemorial,
有一些方法可以在非阻塞套接字上等待某些事件
there has been some way to wait for some event on a non blocking socket.
最初
Originally,
有系统调用select
there was the system calls select,
随着时间的推移
and then over time,
越来越多的可伸缩版本的select已经被发明出来了
more and more scalable versions of select have been invented.
就像在Linux上的投票一样
Like poll on Linux,
他在windows上对Bsd和MacK队列进行了投票
he poll on Bsd and Mac K queue on windows.
有这些Ios完成端口
There is these Ios completion ports.
Python三点四的优点是
The nice thing about Python three point four.
你可以问它一个默认选择器
Is that you can just ask it for a default selector,
它会计算出你的跑步和给你什么
and it will figure out what your running and give you.
最有效的选择器
The most efficient selector.
对于你的平台
For your platform,
所以我们要做一个这样的
so we'll make one of those and.
在我们试着在插座上发送任何东西之前
Before we try to send anything on the socket.
我们将等待它是可读的
We're going to wait for it to be readable.
我们会等着它准备好要讲的东西
We're going to wait for it to be ready for something to be said,
为了做到这一点
so to do that,
我们注册了套接字文件号
we register the sockets file number,
它只是一个整数
which is just an integer.
它只是一个文件描述符
it's just a file descriptor.
我们是否会告诉被选中的人这是一个他们感兴趣的文件号以及我们感兴趣的特定事件
Are we going to tell the selected that this is a file number they were interested in events on and the specific event that we're interested in.
我们想知道什么时候插座是可写的和爱国的吗
Is we want to know when the socket is writable and patriotic?
可以自动为我们导入那个常数吗
Can auto import that constant for us and?
我们要做的下一件事是 到目前为止我们所做的一切都表明我对这个文件描述符感兴趣
The next thing we do so all we have done so far said I'm interested in this event on this file descriptor.
然后 如果我们调用select 它会等待我们要求的事件发生
And then if we call select that will wait for some event that we've asked about to happen.
所以
So,
一旦这种情况发生
once that happens,
我们可以不登记文件号码
we can unregistered the file number.
在这一点上
And by this point.
s是合理的
s is reasonable.
这意味着我们可以合法地调用发送
So that means that we can legally now call send on it.
如果我现在调用这个
So if I call this now.
你会看到我越过这条线
You'll see that I get past this line,
但是现在我们在这里抛出一个异常因为这个套接字是可写的
but now we're throwing an exception down here because the socket is writable,
但是它还没有变得可读 我们还没有等待服务器开始发送它的响应
but it hasn't become readable yet We haven't waited for the server to start sending its response.
所以为了等待
So in order to wait for that,
我们必须再做一次同样的舞蹈
we have to do the same dance again,
这一次我们对权利不感兴趣
and this time we're not interested in right.
能力对可读性很感兴趣
Ability were interested in readability.
所以我们有两条石油格言的输入
So we have two Petro motto inputs that we.
再等一遍
Wait for it again,
一旦这个调用完成
and once this call completes,
那我们就没有登记了
then we'll unregistered.
文件号
The file number,
现在我们可以接收到如果我运行这段代码 它就完成了
and now we're allowed to receive so if I run this code now it completes,
但我们还没有真正想要的东西还花了两秒钟
but we haven't really want anything right still took two seconds.
我们只是把代码弄得一团糟
We just kind of made a small mess in our code.
但我们还没有获得任何效率提升
But we haven't gained any efficiency improvements yet.
那么下一步是什么呢
So what's the next step?
我们之后的下一步
The next step after we've.
开始使用非阻塞套接字
Started to use non blocking sockets,
是回叫
is callbacks.
我将解释它是如何工作的
So I'll explain how that works.
回调是一种允许多个操作同时等待眼睛操作的方法
Callbacks are a way of allowing multiple operations to here waiting concurrently for eye operations.
首先
To begin with,
这是
this get.
当它开始连接时
When it starts connecting,
它需要
it needs to.
一旦套接字可写 注册回调将被执行
Register callback to be executed once the socket is writable,
然后它需要返回 这样工作就可以开始得到另一个欧元当我们在等待连接这个插座的时候
and then it needs to return so that work can begin on getting the other euro while we're waiting to connect this socket right,
为了通过这两秒钟 我们需要某种类型的并发性
we need some sort of concurrency in order to get past this two seconds.
我们来看看它是如何工作的
So let's see how that would work.
我们可以先写回那个调用的主体
We can begin by writing the body of that call back,
所以我把它叫做连接
so I'm gonna call it connected.
这将会执行
This is going to execute.
一旦套接字连接起来 它就会执行下一步
Once the socket is connected and it's going to do the next step.
屁股
Butt.
问题是
The problem is,
你可以看到 写得很高的魅力正在失去它的思想
you can see that written up high charm is sort of losing its mind,
因为在这个新函数中有两个变量没有被绑定因为我们在这里创建了它们
because there's two variables that are not bound in this new function because we created them up here in.
这两个变量是s和request
And the two variables are s and request.
假设这些都是通过某种方式传递的
So let's say that those are passed into connected somehow.
这将会是
And that somehow is going to be.
我们将使用一个登陆器来创建一个闭包来捕获这两个值
We're going to use a lander to create a closure to capture those two values.
所以我们要创建一个Lambda
so we'll create a Lambda.
我们会说 调用Lambda执行与套接字和请求连接
And we'll say that calling the Lambda executes connected with the socket and the request,
我们把这个叫做诽谤回调
and we'll call this slander callback.
现在我们怎么处理这个回叫
Now what do we do with this callback?
选择器国防部寄存器
Well selector Dod register,
它有这个特别的
it has this special.
隐藏
Hidden.
而不是B
Argument instead of a B side,
它被称为数据
and it's called data,
所以我们要把它传递给调用者
so we're going to pass to the called again.
他的数据 因为这是Python
his data because this is Python,
魁北克
the Quebec.
数据可以是任何东西 所以我们要把亚特兰大作为数据
The data can be anything so we're going to pass in Atlanta as the data.
然后呢
And?
我们要等到连接被调用 实际上没有注册那个电话号码
We're going to wait until connected is called to actually unregistered that phone number.
现在
Now,
如果我们这样做
if we do this.
不幸的是
Unfortunately,
我们实际上并没有完成任何工作
we don't actually get any work done.
因为我们的回调从来没有真正执行过
Because our callback is never actually executed.
那么我们如何确保这个回调实际上是在它等待的事件被执行的时候运行呢
So how do we make sure that this callback is actually run once the event that it's waiting for has been executed?
好吧 我们需要的是各种同步框架的第三部分
Well for that we need the third part of various sync framework.
我们需要一个活动
We need an event.
简单地把它切下来
Simply to cut that down here.
Kit将首先运行它会启动一个套接字连接
Kit is going to run first and it's going to start a socket connecting,
然后它会注册一个回调 当套接字是可写的时候就会执行
and then it's going to register a callback to be executed when the socket is writable.
一旦食物完成了
and once food has done that,
它回来了 邓巴也做了同样的事情
it returns and Dunbar does the same thing.
现在我们要讲的是 非阻塞的套接字是开放的 在连接的过程中
So now we've got to say non blocking sockets that are open and in the midst of connected,
它们都已经在选择器中注册了
and they've both been registered with the selector.
所以我要跑了
So I'm going to run.
泥土
A dirt,
简单的小事件循环
simple little event loop here,
但它会说
but it's going to say.
选择器点选择
Selector dot select.
现在让我们通过这里的deBugger 看看选择实际返回的是什么
Now let's run this through the de Bugger here and see what select actually returns.
所以我设置了一个断点
So I set a break point,
现在我们有了这个事件列表
and now we've got this events list,
如果我检查一下
and if I inspect that,
你会看到它是一个列表
you'll see that it's a list.
它有两个元素
It's got two elements,
我们来看看第一个元素是什么
and let's see what that first element is.
它有
It's got.
它是一个有两个值的块茎
It's a tuber with two values.
第二个值不是很有趣
A second value isn't very interesting.
这只是我们一开始传递的面具
This is just the mask that we passed in at first,
它等于事件的正确值
and it's equal to the event right value.
但我们已经知道了 因为那是我们唯一感兴趣的事情
but we already knew that because that was the only event that we were interested in.
它是小管的第一个元素
It's this first element of the tubule.
这个选择器关键的东西很有趣
This selector key thing that's really interesting,
当我调用寄存器时 你会看到我传递的数据值
and you'll see that the data value that I passed in when I called register.
我们在这个事件列表中得到了这个结果它的内容是我注册为回调的亚特兰大
We're getting that back out in this events list and its contents is that Atlanta that I registered as the callback so.
让我们
Let's.
执行
Executed?
这是四个事件
So four event.
以及掩模事件
And mask events.
面具是我们不关心的东西
Mask is the thing we don't care about.
它也是
its too.
它等于完全的事件
It's equal to event outright,
但是这个事件
but this event here.
它的数据字段是我们最初的回调
Its data field is the callback that we originally.
注册了 所以我要叫它CV
registered so I'm going to call that CV,
然后我就叫它
and then I'm just going to call it.
所以如果我现在运行这个 而不是一个断点 看看会发生什么 这样它就可以进入
So if I run this now instead a break point here and see what happens so it can step in.
你会发现我们进入了大满贯赛事
And you'll see that we step into the slam to hear it.
而登陆器呼叫连接和连接是用套接字执行的
And the lander calls connected and connected is executed with the socket.
请求
And the request,
哪个是get
which is get?
我们运行这个
So we run this.
我们将会看到 我们需要在这里做同样的转换来获得特别提款权
We'll see that we need to do the same transformation down here for SDR receive.
我们来做一下
So let's do that.
我们可以说
And we can say.
回调
The callback.
因为当套接字是可写的
For when the socket is writable,
我们会称它为可读 和连接需要的方式是一样的
we're going to call it readable and the same way that connected needed to take thee.
在以前的kolbeck中作为参数可用的变量 在本例中是可读的仍然需要套接字
Variables that had been available in the previous kolbeck as arguments so does readable in this case still needs the socket.
它不需要请求 我们已经完成了
It doesn't need request we're done with that,
但它确实需要一个块的列表
but it does need the list of chunks.
所以它会把这两个作为参数
So it's going to take those two as arguments,
当它被执行时
and when it's executed,
它知道s在这个时候是可读的
it knows that s is readable by this time.
所以它可以加
So it can add,
注册它的文件描述符并接收一辆卡车
register its file descriptor and receive a truck.
我们知道这一块
And we know that a chunk.
嗯
Well,
我们知道这不会引发异常 因为select调用
we know that this won't raise an exception because the select call.
下面这里说 我们在这个插座上等待的任何东西都准备好了
Down here said that whatever we're waiting for on this socket is ready.
所以我们不会扔掉
So we won't throw away.
资源不可用或任何异常
Resource unavailable or whatever that exception was.
数据块将包含一些内容 或者服务器已经关闭
The chunk will either contain something or if the server has closed,
与卡车的连接是空的
the connection than truck is empty.
我们知道我们已经做完了
And we know that we're done.
在这里
So up here,
这意味着我们不调用select
that means that we don't call select,
因为这是事件循环的工作
because that's the event loops job,
但我们确实需要创建回调
but we do need to create the callback.
所以它和我们之前创建的回叫非常相似
So it's going to be very similar to the callback that we created before it's gotta.
是亚特兰大的一个封闭的压力
Be a closure stress by Atlanta,
当我们执行它的时候
and when we execute it.
我们要把插座和卡车
We're going to pass it the socket and the trucks,
这不再是一个循环
and this is no longer a loop.
我们只是注册
We just register.
回调一次 然后我们就做完了
The callback once and then we're done.
这意味着
And that means that,
既然我们不再有一段时间了
since we no longer have a while,
真正的循环
true loop that down here,
如果我们有一块
if we have a chunk,
我们需要等待剩下的部分
we need to wait for the remaining chunks,
所以我们不能就这样离开这里
so we can't just leave here.
我们得走了
We need to go.
返回等于另一个闭包
Call back equals yet another closure,
这将会引起第二个调用或者是对这个可读函数的另一个调用它会再次注册一个选择器来重新注册我们在这里注册的套接字然后这个返回调用不再需要
and that's going to cause a second call or an anther call to this readable function again and will register that again with a selector to re registered the socket that we unregistered up here and then this return calls no longer necessary.
如果我们运行这个
So if we run this.
我们会看到的
We'll see that.
我们的两个请求现在都完成了
Both of our requests now complete.
这太棒了
So that's fantastic,
但不幸的是
but unfortunately.
我们看不到她的最终输出 因为我们在这个狂野的树圈里
We don't see her final output because we're in this wild tree loop,
所以在这个选择器上被阻塞了因为没有什么可以做的了
so were blocked here on this selector because there's nothing left to do,
但是我们还没有让循环完成
but we haven't told the loop to complete,
如果我们点击这里
and if we hit stop here,
我们会看到的
we'll see that.
这条线是
This line is,
事实上
in fact,
我们被困住了
where we're stuck.
所以我认为现在完成这个循环的正确方法是找出所有工作完成后 然后退出循环
So I think that the right way to complete this loop now is to somehow figure out when all work is complete and then exit the loop.
所以我要说的是 有一些任务
So I'm going to say that there is some number of tasks.
这是
That are.
总是在飞行中
Always in flight.
首先
To begin with,
没有
there are none.
无论何时我们打电话
And whenever we call yet.
这一切
It all.
增量
Increment,
任务的数量
the number of tasks.
当我们读完服务器的响应时
And when we have finished reading a response from a server.
那么是时候了
Then it's time to.
有文件记录
Documented?
所以当我们叫食物的时候把任务增加到一个 当我们叫被禁止的时候
So when we call get food that increments the tasks to one and when we call get barred,
这也增加了它
that increments it too,
然后
and then,
当回调的每一个链都运行时
as each of the chains of callbacks runs,
完成
to completion,
这是一种伤害和任务
a detriment and tasks.
直到这个事件循环
Until this event loop.
抓住牙医
Seize the dentist,
0和
says Zero and.
如果我们运行这个
If we run this,
然后我们会看到这两个请求都完成了 奇迹般地只花了一秒钟
then we'll see that both of the requests complete and miraculously it's only taken one second,
不太好
not too.
我们可以做到
and we can do.
哦
Oops.
更多的并发请求 它只需要一秒
Many more of these concurrent requests and it will still only take one second.
这样做的原因是服务器太慢了 以至于这个客户端
And the reason for that is that the server is so slow that this client.
与从服务器上等待下一段时间的花费相比 它不会花费大量的CP处理每一个响应
is not spending significant CP processing each of the responses compared to how long its spending waiting for the next chunk from the server.
服务器需要一个完整的秒才能返回几百字节的数据 而客户端所做的就是将这些数据块向上排列到一个列表中
The server takes a full second to return just a few hundred bytes of data and all the client is doing is upending those chunks to a list.
因此 客户花费几乎没有CP的数据绝大多数时间都在支出
So the data that the client is spending almost no CP with spending overwhelmingly the majority of its time.
等着我
waiting for I am so,
这是一个水槽为之优化的东西
this is the sort of thing that a sink is optimized for.
我们可以用一个简单的框架来做几十个甚至上百个并发的请求 而不是这样
We can do probably dozens or even hundreds of simultaneous requests with a simple framework like this one and not.
在计算上损失大量的时间
Lose significant amounts of time on computation,
它非常高效 因为它不需要保持空闲线程
and it's very efficient because it doesn't have to hold open idle threads.
为了做到这一点
In order to do that.
这很好
So that's great.
它非常高效
It's very efficient,
但你也会发现 与简单的初始实现相比 它是一团乱麻
but you'll also see that it's kind of a mess compared to a very simple initial implementation of Get,
我们现在制造了一堆乱七八糟的东西
we've now created a whole bunch of mess.
我们现在需要三个函数
We now need three functions where,
在我们只有一个之前
before we only had one.
这三个函数
These three functions.
关于它们的特别之处在于 每当一个函数退出时
What's particularly about about them is that each time a function exits,
它失去了所有的局部变量s和请求
it loses all of its local variables right so s and request.
每次回调函数中的一个都完成并注册到要执行的链中的下一个调用
and chunks each time one of these callbacks completes and registers the next call back in the chain to be executed.
它必须手动将它的状态复制到一个闭包中 这样就可以在链的下一个调用中使用这个状态
It has to manually copy its state into a closure so that that state is available to the next call back in the chain.
语言在堆栈和局部变量中提供给我们的常规设备
The normal facilities that the language provides to us in a stack and in local variables,
我们必须手动重新创建这些东西
we have to manually recreate that stuff.
在我们的赛车框架中
In our racing framework.
在爱荷华州的运作中 这种语言对我们来说基本上没有帮助
The language is basically no help to us here in terms of maintaining state across Iowa operations.
所以这个问题的解决方案是下一个阶段
So the solution to this is the next phase.
是窗帘
It's curtains.
窗帘是建立在上面的
And curtains are built on.
未来
Future.
这是我们稍后会在python生成器中看到的类
Which is a class that we'll see in a second on python generators.
在另一个课堂上我们将会看到一个叫做任务的课程
And on another class that we'll see in a moment called Task.
现在有一大堆的东西叫做co例程
Now there are a bunch of kinds of things called co routines.
涂料是非常古老的观念
Coatings are very old idea.
勇气的实现有很多种
There are many kinds of implementations of courage.
在很多语言中 在Python里
teens in many languages in Python,
三个在亚齐
three and in Aceh,
安哥拉
Angola.
哦
Oh,
当我们说勇气的时候
what we mean when we say courage,
意思是
means is.
基于发电机的
Generator based.
胡萝卜素
Carotenes.
格陵兰岛也被称为三点五年的常规和影响
Greenland's are also called co routines and impact on three point five.
现在有了新的东西 叫做本地代码例程 可以利用新的饮食和权重关键字
There are now new things called native code routines that can take advantage of the new eating and weight keywords.
它们本质上是在发电机上面的语法糖
They're essentially syntactic sugar on top of generators.
所以如果你理解他们现在将要讨论的内容
So if you understand the discussion they were going to have right now,
您将了解Python的三个要点
you'll understand how the Python three point.
5个本地代码例程也可以工作
five native code routines work as well,
尽管它们是内置在解释器里而不是用发电机制造的
although they're built into the interpreter rather than built out of generators,
这是我们现在要做的
the way we're going to do right now.
所以
So.
我们首先需要的是一个未来的课程
The first thing that we need is a future class.
你们会看到为什么
And you'll see why in a little bit,
这很有用
this is useful,
但是现在我要展示的是
but for the moment I'm just going to presented,
你只需要相信我这将会是一个有用的东西
and you'll just have to trust me that this is going to be a useful thing,
因此 未来代表着一些悬而未决的事件
so a future represents some pending event.
他们在等着
They were waiting for.
它有一个将被执行的回调列表
It has a list of callbacks that will be executed.
当这个事件发生时
When that event occurs,
and when that event occurs,
有人会说决心 未来会
somebody's going to call resolve and the future will.
执行所有等待该事件的回调
Execute all of the callbacks that were waiting for that event.
这就是我们未来的课程
So that's our future class.
我们要做这个简单的变换而不是直接用选择器来注册和回调
And we're going to do this simple transformation where instead of register and callbacks directly with the selector,
我们要注册期货
we're going to register futures instead.
所以我们将回调添加到回调的列表中
So we add the callback to the list of callbacks.
等待这个未来的解决 而不是直接注册回调
waiting for this future to be resolved and instead of registering the callback directly.
我们把未来登记在册
We register the future instead.
我也要做同样的事情
And I have to do the same thing.
这里
Here.
最后
And finally,
我们必须这样做
we have to do.
同样艰辛的转变
That same laborious transformation.
在这里
Here,
所以
so,
在我们注册回调的三个地方
in the three places where we had registered callbacks,
我们现在加入了对期货的回调 并对未来进行了登记
we're now adding callbacks to futures and registering the future instead.
这意味着在我们的事件循环中
And that means that down here in our event loop.
数据不再是对其未来的呼唤
The event that data is no longer a call back its future,
所以我们不直接叫它
and so we don't call it directly.
相反
Instead,
我们说了我们的决心
we say futured our resolve.
所以
So.
你可以期待
You can expect,
有了这样一个简单的转变 很可能是正确的
with such a simple transformation that had probably got it right,
看起来我是这样做的
and it looks like I did so.
到目前为止 我们所做的一切都是为了她的代码
All we've done so far as made her code.
更糟糕的是
even worse,
更加混乱和漫长
even more messy and long,
我们得到的结果和之前的一样
and we have simply got the same performance that we had before.
所以下一步就是用这些期货和发电机来开始实施飓风
So the next step is going to be to somehow use these futures with generators to start to implement hurricanes.
所以我要快速复习一下
So I'm going to do a quick little refresher about.
发电机造成了一些令人困惑的事情
Generators cause there's a few confusing things about them.
即使是经验丰富的python程序
Even for veteran python programs.
生成器是用生成器创建的
So a generator is created with a generator,
函数和生成器
function and a generator.
函数是任何包含的函数
Function is any function that contains.
收益表
The yield statement.
所以这个生成器函数将会打印
So this generator function is going to print,
开始生产1
start yield one.
中间
Middle.
还有
Too.
然后就完成了
And then it's done.
生成器函数的有趣之处在于 当你执行它时
And the funny thing about a generator function is that when you execute it,
它实际上并没有运行它的代码
it doesn't actually run its code.
它没有打印
It didn't print,
从中间开始 或者做相反的事情
start middle or done instead.
它创建了一个生成器对象和这个生成器对象
It created a generator object and this generator object.
包含一个代码对象来设置表示这些东西的字节码
Contains a code object sets the byte code that represents this stuff.
然后呢
And?
它有
It's got.
40个字节 生成器也有一个堆栈框架
Forty four bytes and the generator also has a stack frame.
它有一个指令指针
And that's got an instruction pointer,
它开始了他的负1
and it begins his negative one,
也就是说它还没有执行任何指令
meaning that it hasn't executed any instructions yet.
这就是为什么我们没有看到这些指纹的原因
And that's why we didn't actually see any of these prints.
大坝正在被执行
Dam is being executed.
那么去哪里呢
So the way to?
运行一个生成器就是在它旁边调用它
Run a generator is to call him next on it.
如果你这样做
And if you do that,
然后你会看到它执行了最初的几段字节码
then you'll see that it executes its first few bites of byte code,
所以它打印开始 一个实际上是下一个语句的返回值因为下一个语句的返回值是下一个执行的结果
so it prints start and one is actually the return value of the next statement because the return value of next is whichever yield his next executed.
现在 指令指针被暂停了13次 进入了40个字节的Baker
And the instruction pointer is now paused at thirteen bites into the forty four bytes of Baker.
所以如果我们下次再打电话
So if we call next again this time,
我要在它的返回值上签名 这样你就能看到一个中间的王子
I'm going to sign its return value so that you can see that a prince middle.
但它又回来了
But it returns.
还有
Too.
这是传递到下一个yield语句的值
Which was the value passed into the next yield statement.
现在我们的堆栈指针
And now our stack pointer.
对不起
Sorry,
我们的指示指针是四十四的二十八
our instruction pointer is at twenty eight of forty four.
如果我们再打一次电话
And if we call next one more time.
然后我们将提高停止迭代异常
Then we'll raise stop iteration exception,
这说明了什么
which indicates that?
它已经完成了 最后一个指针已经被删除了
It's done executing and the last I pointer has actually been deleted.
这就是生成器如何在二点五版本的Python中工作的
So that's how a generator works in all versions of Python going back two point five.
那么我们如何用它来制作窗帘呢
So how do we use that to create a curtain?
嗯
Well,
这是我的承诺
here's the promise.
我们的承诺是这样的
The promise is going to be that.
这是函数
This get function.
它现在必须创建一个闭包 以捕获他的局部变量
Which currently has to create a closure that captures his local variables.
关闭调用的名称
Names that closure call back.
向未来返回的广告 然后用选择器注册未来
Ads that call back to the future and then registers that future with the selector.
这可以简化为不需要回电话
This can be simplified to not require a call back at all.
所以我要离开回调
So I'm going to leave the callback.
我要删除回调主体
I'm going to delete the callbacks body.
但我们需要
But we need to.
暂停
Pause until,
在我们未注册之前 在这里是可写的 然后依靠套接字是可读的 这样我们就可以在它上面调用发送
as is writable somehow here before we unregistered and then rely on the socket to be readable so that we can call send on it and.
我们的承诺是
The promise is that somehow,
通过F
by yielding F,
我们刚刚创造的未来
the future that we just created.
我们可以暂停这个生成器 直到我们说我们感兴趣的事件发生
Somehow we can pause this generator until the event that we said we were interested in has occurred.
如果我们相信这个承诺是真的
And if we believe that this promise is true.
然后 我们可以将两个函数合并成一个包含yield语句的单一生成函数
Then we can combine what had been two functions into a single generative function that contains a yield statement.
屁股
Butt.
这个承诺还没有实现 因为如果我运行这个
The promise is not going to be fulfilled just yet because if I run this,
它将花费0秒
it's going to take zero seconds.
它没有输出
It has no output,
它没有做功
and it doesn't do any work.
为什么呢
So why is that?
这里发生了什么
What happened here?
嗯
Well,
回想一下 当你执行一个生成器函数时
recall that when you execute a generator function,
它会返回
it returns.
生成器实际上并不运行它的任何代码
A generator doesn't actually run any of its code.
现在我在这里添加了一个yield语句
So now that I've added a yield statement here to get,
这意味着到达这里
that means that get here.
只需要返回一个生成器
Just returns a generator.
什么都不做
doesn't actually do anything,
这里也是一样
and the same here.
那么我们要怎么做呢
So how are we going to?
执行它
Execute it?
我们怎么称呼它呢
How do we call next on it?
这就是这个问题的第三个部分
So that is the third piece of this puzzle of this co.
基于例程的基本框架是任务
Routine based basic framework is the task.
测试类
The test class.
它负责在发电机上调用next
It's responsible for calling next on generators.
我们来看看它是什么样的
So let's see what that looks like.
在未来和任务的情况下
And in the case of both future and task,
这些想法非常简单 过于简单 而且不完整
these are incredibly simple and oversimplified and buggy incomplete implementations of these ideas.
这些想法在许多框架中得到了充分的表达
These ideas are fully expressed in a number of frameworks,
尤其是龙卷风和现在的情况
notably tornado and now in.
我在python里踱步
Pacing I owe in the python.
标准库的3点
Three point for the standard library.
所以我的任务类的哑版本会是这样的
So my dumb version of the task class is going to look like.
我们将用生成器初始化它
We're going to initialize it with a generator.
我将保存它
I will save that.
然后我们会有一个叫做Step的函数
And then we'll have a function called Step,
这个术语是从桑丘那里借来的
and this terminology is borrowed from a Sancho.
他下一步在发电机上的呼叫是什么
What step does his calls next on the generator?
从发电机开始
And since the generator,
它将会产生一个未来
it's going to yield a future.
这就变成了下一个的返回值
So that's going to become the return value of next.
我们来捕获它
So let's capture that.
然后
And then.
当这个未来得到解决时 我们想要发生什么
What do we want to happen when this future is resolved?
我们需要给未来增加一些电话
We need to add some kind of call back to the future,
这是我们想要在未来做好的事情
something that we want to happen once the future is ready and.
让我们把self step作为回调
Let's just pass self dot step in as the callback.
所以一旦这个未来得到解决
So once this future is resolved,
就会回到这里 然后再来 自我怀疑再次出现
will just come right back into here and will come next and self doubt turn again.
我们会再打电话给自己
Will we call next and self de Jean again,
这将在这里继续
that's going to resume here.
因此我们知道我们可以注册套接字文件号
And therefore we know that we can and register the sockets file number,
而现在的情况是可信的
and that s is now credible.
所以如果我们运行它 它仍然不会起作用
So if we run this still not going to work.
这样做的原因是
The reason for that is.
我们需要做一个初始的调用自我那一步
That we need to make an initial call the self that step,
说
said,
爸爸
Dad,
我们给self做了一个初始的调用 这样我们就得到了启动函数
we make an initial call to self that Jen so that we get the get function started,
它会连接套接字 等等
and it will connect the socket and so on.
我们在这里做一下
So let's just do that right here.
在构造函数中
In the constructor.
然后是最后一步
And then the final step.
这个转换将会在下面
Of this conversion is going to be down here,
我们需要包装的地方
where we need to wrap.
在一个任务中 每一个调用 当返回一个生成器时
Each of these calls in a task so when get returns a generator,
任务
the task,
拉普说
Rapp said.
香肠的标志 叫self step 我将会调用它 它实际上会开始这个东西直到第一个产量
Signs of sausage and calls self dot step and I will call next in that will actually begin this thing executing up until the first yield.
斯蒂芬
Stephen.
如果我运行这个
So if I run this.
在某种程度上
In a way,
你会看到我们取得进步的方式
you will see the way we make progress.
因为我们在这里提出了一个停止迭代异常
Because we raise a stop iteration exception here.
所以这确实是个好消息
So that that actually that's good news,
因为这意味着这个get生成器实际上已经运行到完成了
because it means that this get generator has actually been run to completion.
它完成了它所要做的工作
It's done the work that it set out to do.
所以
so.
如果我们
if we.
抓住它
Catch that.
我们想在这里做什么
What do we want to do here?
嗯
Well,
任务完成了
the task is done.
让我们返回
So let's just return.
如果我们执行这个版本
And if we execute this version.
它实际上完成了
It actually completes.
这太棒了 我们还有一些零散的回调
So this is fantastic now we've still got a few stray callbacks.
所以
So.
我们可以消去这些和我们在这里做的变换
We can get rid of those the same transformation that we did here.
所以我们也要把它写下来
So we're just going to do it down here again as well,
所以我们要
so we're going to.
我们再也不需要这个电话了
We don't need this call back any more.
你不需要把它加到未来
You don't need to add it to the future.
我们仍然需要说出我们感兴趣的事件并注册未来当事件发生时
We do still need to say what event we're interested in and register the future to be resolved when that event occurs,
但是我们可以删除回调定义
but we can delete the callback definition.
因为我们的函数和之前的一样
Since we're still in the same function as we were in before,
我们不需要一个冗余的全局声明
we don't need a redundant global statement.
如果我们简单地创造出我们创造的新未来
And if we simply yield this new future that we created,
这意味着
that means that.
到目前为止
By now,
当任务解决的时候
by the time the task resolve resumes us,
这个套接字现在是可读的
the socket is now readable.
这是最后一个回调
And here we've got our last of the callback.
我们可以把它删掉
so we can delete that.
我们可以实现我们的未来 而不是注册一个回调
And we can yield our future instead of registering a callback.
啊
And ah.
当我们收到下一个查克时 我们想做什么
What do we want to do once we have received the next Chuck?
换句话说
In other words,
一旦套接字再次被写出来
once the socket is writable again?
嗯
Well,
我们想要得到下一个杰克
we want to receive the next jack right,
所以我们最后要做的是 我们最终会复制原来在d里的真实循环
so what we're going to end up doing is we're going to end up reproducing the same while true loop that we originally had in d.
在演讲开始的时候
Olden days at the beginning of this talk,
当我们写一个简单的阻塞时
when we were writing a simple blocking yet.
所以它看起来是这样的
So that's going to look something like.
我们要
We're going to.
把这个放在循环中
Put this within the loop.
每次通过循环 我们会说
And each time through the loop we say,
我想从插座上读取数据
I want to read from the socket,
所以等待这个未来的解决
so wait for this future to be resolved.
然后从选择器中取消套接字
And then unregistered the socket from the selector.
得到那块
get the chunk.
如果有任何东西被添加到列表中 这个东西现在是额外的
And if there is any then added to the list and this stuff is now extra.
这个循环会重复 在这里重复做这些
The loop will just repeat and do that stuff again up here,
如果没有查克
and if there's no chuck.
这意味着
That means that.
我们已经阅读了服务器响应
We're done reading the server response,
所以我们可以
and so we can.
把身体连接起来
Join the body up,
打印第一行 减少任务数
print the first line decrement the tasks count,
从现在开始 我们又回到了一个无限循环
and since now we're in an infinite loop again.
在这里 我们需要尽快返回
here we need to return as soon as we're done.
现在
Now,
如果一切顺利 我运行这个
if all goes well and I run this,
然后它仍然需要一秒
then it still takes one second.
它仍然在做所有的工作
it still does all the work that it was.
当被要求做的时候 我们仍然可以把它扩展到大量的任务而不损失任何性能
Asked to do and we can still scale this out to a large number of tasks without any loss of performance,
因为发射10个15个窗帘实在是太便宜了
because launching ten fifteen curtains is incredibly cheap,
它的价格大概和
it's roughly as cheap as.
一堆回叫
A bunch of callbacks.
所以很酷的例程是两个世界中最好的 他最便宜的回调比我的系统上的线程要便宜得多
So cool routines are kind of the best of both worlds there about his cheapest callbacks are much cheaper than threads on my system,
我测量了一个co例程
I measured that a co routine takes.
大约6K的内存和30个线程的内存
About six K of memory versus about thirty cave memory for a thread,
此外 我做了一个小实验 发现我有能力启动超过十万个常规程序
and furthermore I did a little experiment and found that I was capable of launching over a hundred thousand co routines.
它们的限制仅仅是允许Python进程分配的ram数量
Their limited only by the amount of ram that the Python process is allowed to allocate.
丝丝太太
Mrs Threads,
除了简单的内存限制之外 它还受到其他限制
which are subject to other limits beside simply memory limits.
有各种用户和操作系统限制了进程被允许开始的线程数量
There are various user and operating system limits on the number of threads that a process is allowed to start with.
她
Her.
在不同的工作方式下
Difficult in various ways to work around,
它们占用了空间和操作系统数据结构和操作系统调度器 最终导致它们的开销变得非常重要
and they take up space and operating system data structures and the operating system scheduler that eventually causes their overhead to become quite significant.
他们所做的一切都是在等待爱荷华州的一些缓慢的行动它们实际上需要非常多的sepia所以与这种应用的煤例程相比
All they're doing is waiting around for some sort of slow Iowa operations that are actually going to require very much sepia so compared to coal routines for a application like this,
这将花费很少的时间进行计算 并且绝大多数时间都花在等待一个缓慢的服务器或者在套接字的另一端的慢客户机上
that's going to spend very little time doing computation and overwhelmingly spending its time waiting for a slow server or a slow client at the other end of the socket.
在这种情况下 Co例程更有效率
Co routines are much more efficient for this kind of thing,
但是和回叫相比 它们的简单得多 因为
but compared to call backs their lot simpler because.
你可以把所有的代码放在一个函数里
You can put all of the code for a coating in one function,
所以你不需要声明并注册整个回调函数链
so you don't have to declare and register a whole chain of callbacks.
你可以重复使用你的局部变量 就像你经常遇到的麻烦一样
And you can just reuse your local variables the same way that trouble you have always done.
这就是龙卷风的开始或者是水槽的开始
So that's the beginning of Tornado style or a sink.
基于Ios风格的同步框架
Ios Style Co routine based a sync framework.
如果你想了解更多
So if you want to know more about this,
去斜杠的co例程为你创建了一个登陆页面它会把你链接到我刚才写的代码的一个版本
go to bitterly slash co routines have created a landing page for you there that'll link you out to a version of the code that I wrote just now,
我和吉多范罗斯姆一起写了一章 这一章将会出现在开源应用程序架构的下一本书中
as well as link you to a chapter that I wrote with Guido van Rossum that will appear in the next book in the architecture of Open source Application Serious.
这一章更详细地介绍了如何在水槽中实现基于发电机的涂层
and that chapter goes into far more detail about how generator based coatings are implemented in a sink.
我在一个标准的图书馆里养了一只宠物
I owned a pet on three point for a standard library,
特别是它涉及到如何
and especially it goes into how.
Co例程利用了
Co routines take advantage of.
特定于python3的生成器特性以及在任何场景中包含的同步队列类
Generator features that are specific to python three and how a synchronous queue class that's included in any scenario,
可以用一种对习惯使用线程的人非常熟悉的方式来协调日常工作
can be used to coordinate co routines in a way that's very familiar to people who are used to using threads.
作为一个提醒
And as a reminder,
如果你想和我这样的人在一家opensource公司工作
if you want to work with people like me at a opensource company,
这是非常温暖的 多样性有真正的实现和技术挑战的工作
that's very warm and diversity has really fulfilling and technically challenging jobs.
Mongodb正在招聘
Mongo db is hiring.
我们在纽约的帕罗奥图和世界各地都设有办事处
We have offices in New York in Palo Alto and worldwide.
去bewdley 砍去商店
Go to bewdley slash mongo dashed shops.
我很想和你一起工作
I would love to work with you.